<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: code | Anton Katunin]]></title>
  <link href="http://antulik.com/blog/categories/code/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://antulik.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-15T10:23:07+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://antulik.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anton Katunin]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[antulik@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging Poltergeist and PhantomJS]]></title>
    <link href="http://antulik.com/blog/2015/05/27/debugging-poltergeist/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-27T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://antulik.com/blog/2015/05/27/debugging-poltergeist</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently at Opensight we had weird issue with our integration tests. When we run single test it succeeds, but when whole suit it fails.</p>

<p>It was failing on the same &ldquo;terms and conditions&rdquo; page where we expect &lsquo;Accept&rsquo; button: <code>could not find element Accept</code></p>

<pre><code class="ruby">click_button 'Accept'
</code></pre>

<!--more-->


<p>So we started digging. First of all I&rsquo;ve verified that response from all requests is the same.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">after_filter do
  puts response.body
end
</code></pre>

<p>And in fact it was the same all the time.</p>

<p>The next step was to verify what html is received by <code>PhantomJS</code></p>

<pre><code class="ruby">puts "html=#{page.html}"
click_button 'Accept'
</code></pre>

<p>Strangely enough the first time it was proper html, but after it was empty html.</p>

<pre><code class="html">&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>Very strange indeed. The next step was to debug PhantomJS and Poltergeist.</p>

<p>Poltergeist has the option to debug network requests, so we can print to log.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">page.driver.network_traffic.each do |r|
  r.response_parts.each do |resp|
    puts resp.inspect
  end
end
page.driver.clear_network_traffic
click_button 'Accept'
</code></pre>

<p>After looking at response code, we&rsquo;ve found that the first request it gets <code>200 Ok</code> response code. But the following requests to the same page <code>304 Non modified</code>.</p>

<p>Aha! Bingo! It looks it&rsquo;s something to do with caching. Let&rsquo;s try to enable <code>disk-cache</code>.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">Capybara.register_driver :poltergeist do |app|
  Capybara::Poltergeist::Driver.new(app,
    :phantomjs_options =&gt; ['--disk-cache=true'],
  )
end
Capybara.javascript_driver = :poltergeist
</code></pre>

<p>Bingo Two!! Now the whole test suit works as expected.</p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>It seems like a bug in PhantomJS 2.0 so that cache is not stored, while it should be.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Circular dependency in Rails]]></title>
    <link href="http://antulik.com/blog/2014/11/09/ciruclar-dependency-in-rails/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-09T11:01:39+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://antulik.com/blog/2014/11/09/ciruclar-dependency-in-rails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is an interesing bug I&rsquo;ve encountered this week. While our Rails application was working in development it was completely broken in UAT environment (which is 99% production like)</p>

<p>We were getting <code>Circular dependency detected while autoloading constant</code> error on all of our reports.</p>

<p>Not so long ago we&rsquo;ve extracted group of controllers in its own rails engine with isolated namespace <code>Merchant</code>. After some investigation we&rsquo;ve spotted the bug, let&rsquo;s see if you can find it.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">module Merchant
  class Reports::PostsController &lt; ApplicationController
  # some code here
  end
end
</code></pre>

<p>Do you see it? It&rsquo;s not obvious is it? How about these alternatives:</p>

<!--more-->


<pre><code class="ruby">module Merchant
  module Reports
    class PostsController &lt; ApplicationController
    # some code here
    end
  end
end
</code></pre>

<pre><code class="ruby">module Merchant::Reports
  class PostsController &lt; Merchant::ApplicationController
  # some code here
  end
end
</code></pre>

<pre><code class="ruby">class Merchant::Reports::PostsController &lt; Merchant::ApplicationController
  # some code here
end
</code></pre>

<p>All of these work except the first one. What&rsquo;s going on here? My guess will be</p>

<ol>
<li>Rails loads <code>Merchant::Reports::PostsController</code> controller</li>
<li>It looks for <code>Merchant::ApplicationController</code> and loads it</li>
<li><code>Merchant::ApplicationController</code> somehow triggers the load of <code>Merchant</code> module, which loads all classes in it.</li>
<li>repeat</li>
<li>Show <code>Circular dependency detected while autoloading constant</code> error</li>
</ol>


<p>So the fix was to rewrite it with different ruby style.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multiple logins at once with Browser Profiles]]></title>
    <link href="http://antulik.com/blog/2014/09/21/multiple-logins-at-once/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-21T00:00:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://antulik.com/blog/2014/09/21/multiple-logins-at-once</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Do you:</p>

<ul>
<li>share same computer and login with other family members</li>
<li>or you are testing website with login</li>
</ul>


<p>Then you should know what <em>browser profiles</em> are.</p>

<p><strong>Browser profiles</strong> is a way to separate usage of the web browser per user. Just like any login system but without password. That means history, cache, cookies and as a result logins will be scope to a single user.</p>

<p>This is ideal when you are testing website for different logins at the same time or just want to separate work and personal browsing history.</p>

<p>Separation of browsing history might get more important with time as it&rsquo;s emerging trend for search enginge to personalise search results.</p>

<p>Most popular browsers have browser profiles built in already:</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/2364824?hl=en">Chrome</a> (Manage multiple users on Chrome)</li>
<li><a href="https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/profile-manager-create-and-remove-firefox-profiles">Firefox</a> (Multi profile access)</li>
<li><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/ie/archive/2009/05/06/session-cookies-sessionstorage-and-ie8.aspx">Internet Explorer</a> (Session Cookies, sessionStorage, and IE8 or “How can I log into two webmail accounts at the same time?”)</li>
</ol>


<p>Other references:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.howtogeek.com/139705/how-to-use-multiple-browser-profiles-in-any-browser/">How to Use Multiple Browser Profiles in Any Browser</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Differentiate your gem]]></title>
    <link href="http://antulik.com/blog/2014/09/14/differentiate-your-gem/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-14T00:00:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://antulik.com/blog/2014/09/14/differentiate-your-gem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Are you tired of seeing <em>yet another project</em> on github while there are ten others which do exactly the same thing? In this post I suggest we start to diffirentiate our projects.</p>

<p>Projects like <a href="ruby-toolbox.com">Ruby Toolbox</a> make developers life much easiers by categorising gems and what&rsquo;s more important providing popularity information. It is important because developer can make make his own decision why one gem is better than other one.</p>

<p>The first question I&rsquo;m looking answer for in such situation is <strong>how this gem or project on github is different from another one</strong>, almost identical as it seems at first.</p>

<p>I believe every single library should have the first two sections in its readme file:</p>

<ul>
<li>What is it? And how can it make my life better?</li>
<li>How is it different from competitor projects?</li>
</ul>


<p>So when you think your new project is going to change the world and there are none like it in existance. You can save yourself some time and delete it after <em>initial  commit</em>.</p>

<p>Save time for your fellow developers, be honest and tell why we should and shouldn&rsquo;t use your library.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speed up POW DNS Lookup]]></title>
    <link href="http://antulik.com/blog/2013/09/01/pow/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-01T00:00:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://antulik.com/blog/2013/09/01/pow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m using <a href="http://pow.cx/">POW</a> as a proxy to my local dev server in development. That gives me nice local *.dev domain names. However I&rsquo;ve noticed that it takes 10 seconds to load a singe page in Chrome. Of course, I thought, It does like 80 requests as each asset is served as a separate file in development. But after investigating it a bit more DNS lookup for each request was 3 seconds and for some reasons it was like that for every single http request.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>After looking around turns out that the issue DNS resolver checks my main DNS server first if it knows anything about *.dev domains, if not then it checks the next dns server and so on. Which results in 3 seconds delay.</p>

<p>Solution.
First thing. I had &lsquo;default&rsquo; rule in pow to proxy port 3000 if now specific domains was matched. So I&rsquo;ve added app specific domain I was using for the development -> storyline which gave me storyline.dev</p>

<p>Second. I&rsquo;ve installed <a href="https://github.com/Rodreegez/powder">powder</a></p>

<pre><code>gem install powder
</code></pre>

<p>and used host command to write my domains into the /etc/hosts file</p>

<pre><code>powder host
</code></pre>

<p>after that DNS lookup decreased from 3s to 1ms. Pretty good time saver.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
